<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lawrence Mayor. Comm. Concil. tent. vicesimo septimo die Januarii, anno Dom. 1664. Annoque regni Regis Caroli Secundi nunc Angliæ, &amp;c. Decimo sexto</title>
            <author>City of London (England). Court of Common Council.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1675</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 78 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 24 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A48999</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L2854N</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R216799</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99828517</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99828517</idno>
            <idno type="VID">32945</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A48999)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 32945)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1954:13)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Lawrence Mayor. Comm. Concil. tent. vicesimo septimo die Januarii, anno Dom. 1664. Annoque regni Regis Caroli Secundi nunc Angliæ, &amp;c. Decimo sexto</title>
                  <author>City of London (England). Court of Common Council.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>45, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1675?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>A collection of acts concerning woodmongers, each with caption title, with dates ranging from 1664-1674.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect? Title page lacking; title taken from caption title on A2r.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Wood --  Commerce --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>London (England) --  History --  17th century.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Charles II, 1660-1685 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:32945:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <div type="part">
               <head>
                  <hi>LAWRENCE MAYOR.</hi> Com. Concil. tent. Viceſimo ſeptimo die <hi>Januarii,</hi> Anno Dom. <hi>1664.</hi> Annoque Regni Regis <hi>CAROLI</hi> Secundi nunc Angliae, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Decimo ſexto.</head>
               <p>THe Right Honourable the Lord Mayor, ſignifying unto this Court, that ſeveral Complaints have been made to the Court of Aldermen, of the late Raiſing of the Prizes, and abuſes uſed in the Meaſure and Weight of <hi>Coals;</hi> And that His Majeſty hath alſo taken notice thereof to his Lordſhip, and ſignified His Pleaſure, That ſome ſpeedy courſe be taken for remedy therein. And that ſeveral Judges of the Land, and other great Perſonages have diſcourſed and given advice to his Lordſhip to like purpoſe.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And further,</hi> That a Committee of the Court of Aldermen, appointed upon this occaſion, have (upon a diligent inquiry into the cauſes of the ſaid Complaints) repreſented the ſame, together with ſome means for remedy thereof, in a Report to the ſaid Court of Alder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men; which upon deſire of this Court, was now Read for their better Information.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>It is therefore thought fit and Ordered,</hi> That the ſaid Committee of the Court of Aldermen, namely, Sir <hi>William Turner,</hi> Sir <hi>Richard Rives,</hi> Mr. Alderman <hi>Hooker,</hi> Mr. Alderman <hi>Thomas Bonfoy,</hi> together with Sir <hi>William Bateman,</hi> Sir <hi>Arthur Ingram,</hi> Mr. Deputy <hi>Nevill,</hi> Mr. Deputy <hi>Fluellin,</hi> Sir <hi>Thomas Chamberlain,</hi> Mr. <hi>Penning,</hi> Coll. <hi>Cleggatt,</hi> and Mr. Deputy <hi>Canham,</hi> or any two of the ſaid Aldermen, and four of the ſaid
<pb facs="tcp:32945:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                  <pb n="1" facs="tcp:32945:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                  <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="2" facs="tcp:32945:3"/> Commoners, ſhall take further conſideration of the ſaid Complaints and Abuſes, and of the moſt ſpeedy and effectual means to remedy the ſame, for the general good of His Majeſties Subjects, in and about this City, and parts adjacent, and vindication of the Goverment and good Order of the ſame City from ſuch Aſpertions and prejudice, as (by relation) are imputed to it, by occaſion of the ſaid Complaints and Abuſes; And certify unto this Court in writing under their Hands, how they find the ſame, and their Opinions therein; and <hi>Richard Hinde</hi> to warn and attend them.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>
                  <hi>LAWRENCE MAYOR.</hi> Com. Concil. tent. Decimo quarto die <hi>Februarii,</hi> Anno Dom. <hi>1664.</hi> Anno Regni Regis <hi>CAROLI</hi> nunc Angliae, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Decimo ſeptimo.</head>
               <p>THis Day the Committee appointed by late Order of this Court, to conſider of ſeveral Abuſes complained to be committed by the <hi>Wood-mongers,</hi> in and about the Price, Meaſure, and Weight of Coals, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And of Remedies for the ſame, did deliver into this Court a Report in Writing under their Hands, how they find the ſame, and their Opini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons; the tenor whereof is as followeth, <hi>viz.</hi>
               </p>
               <q>
                  <pb n="3" facs="tcp:32945:3"/>
                  <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                     <body>
                        <div type="report">
                           <head>To the Right Honourable the Lord Mayor, the Right Worſhipful the Aldermen his Brethren, and Commons of the City of <hi>London,</hi> in Common-Council aſſembled.</head>
                           <p>
                              <hi>WHereas</hi> by a late Order of this Honourable Court, intimating the Complaints lately made to your good Lordſhip, and the Court of Aldermen, of the exceſſive Prizes and Deceits uſed in the Mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure and Weight of Coals; and that His Majeſty had taken notice thereof, and ſignified his pleaſure for ſome ſpeedy courſe to remedy the ſame; alſo that ſeveral of the Judges and other great Perſonages had diſcourſed thereof, and given ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice to your Lordſhip to like purpoſe, which had occaſioned an inquiry to be made into the cauſes of the ſaid complaints, by a Committee therefore appointed by your Lordſhip, and the ſaid Court of Aldermen; whoſe Report thereof, was then read in this Court for their better information, and this Court was pleaſed thereupon to refer it unto us, whoſe Names are ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed, to take further conſideration of the ſaid Matters, and of the moſt ſpeedy and effectual Means to redreſs the ſame. <hi>Now We,</hi> the ſaid Committees, do humbly certifie, that We have heard and received the Evidence and Informa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion offered by diverſe knowing and credible Perſons, touching the ſaid Complaints and Abuſes, and (beſides that many of the particulars are notorious and obvious to common Experience) do find upon the ſaid Informations, which the Parties reſpectively do offer to confirm by their Oaths, That the Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens and Inhabitants of <hi>London,</hi> and Parts adjacent, do lye under an intollerable grievance in the Caſes above men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned, brought upon them by the <hi>Wood-mongers,</hi> as by a
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:32945:4"/> ſummary Accompt of their Practices and Abuſes contained in the enſuing particulars, more plainly may appear.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>And firſt,</hi> Touching the Price of Sea-Coals, it appears, that the ſame is, and is uſed and ſubject to be raiſed by the <hi>Wood-mongers,</hi> at their own pleaſure, and that by theſe ſeveral means and practices, eſpecially, <hi>Firſt,</hi> the <hi>Wood-mongers</hi> pretending to the ſole Trade of retailing Coals, and aiming to compaſs the ſame, and to exclude all others, have, in order to that end, Firſt obtained diverſe, and do take all opportunities to obtain more of the Wharfs in and about the City, into their own hands, and do convert ſo many as can be ſpared from their own occaſions, to other uſes, binding their Tenants under ſtrict Covenants and Limitations, not to im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploy the ſame, or but very ſparingly, for the Landing or Selling of Coals, That by depriving of others, they only may have thoſe advantages of Landing, Storing, and Selling of that and all other Fuel.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Secondly,</hi> where they cannot obtain poſſeſſion of any other Fuel-Wharfs in their way, they deal with the Owners to change the ſame to other uſes.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Thirdly,</hi> They diſturb and hinder the Coal-Ships from Unlading at <hi>Smarts</hi> Key, (as was formerly uſed) and other known and convenient Keys and Places, ſo to compel them to their own Wharfs, whereby the Citizens and others, are diſappointed of Buying there at the firſt hand, and by the good Meaſure of the <hi>Coal-Meeters,</hi> and of the ready carriage they were wont to have from thoſe places.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Fourthly,</hi> They labour to ſuppreſs all others that deal in Retailing of Coals, denying them for Engroſſers, and impo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing upon the eaſier and meaner ſort, Arbitrary Fines, and proſecuting others at Law, denying to all the benefit of Carr-rooms, or the uſe of the Town Carrs to ſerve their Cuſtomers, and puniſhing the Carr-men with penalties and troubles, and ſeizure of their Carrs, if they diſcover them in ſuch Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployment,
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:32945:4"/> ſo to conſtrain them to keep up their ſtores to their loſs, and the publick damage, or to put them off to the <hi>Wood-mongers</hi> upon their own terms, for their better advantage of raiſing the Price, when they have engroſſed the whole Store in their own hands. <hi>Whereas</hi> indeed, the Buying and Selling of Coals, is but an accident to the <hi>Wood-mongers</hi> Trade, and free for all men to uſe as themſelves, and to en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courage the multiplicity of Traders in Victual and Fuel, (eſpecially, that are not united into one Society and Combi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation) hath been ever held a moſt certain means to keep down the Price of thoſe Proviſions, and at this time, we find thoſe other Retailers willing to Sell by the juſt Meaſures, and at much lower Rates than the <hi>Wood-mongers</hi> do, if they could be ſupplyed with Carrs to ſerve out their Coals to the Buyers.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Fifthly,</hi> They generally obſtruct their own Apprentices, after their times are expired, from Setting up, by diſappoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting them of Wharfs, and denying them Carr-rooms, as a further means to continue the Trade Engroſſed in a few hands.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Sixthly,</hi> They deny their own, nor will ſuffer, but in all they can, diſcourage and hinder the Town Carrs from carrying home the Coals of private Perſons, which are not bought of themſelves, thereby hindring all perſons of ſupplies from the Ships at the firſt hand, where they would receive much better Meaſure, beſides the advantage of the Ingrain, and at far eaſier Prizes than are afforded by the <hi>Wood-mon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers;</hi> ſo that if theſe reſtraints be put upon the Trade by the <hi>Wood-mongers,</hi> for their own private Gain, in a time of ſo vaſt increaſe of Houſes and Inhabitants, within this City, and parts adjacent, an advance of the Price of Sea-Coals muſt neceſſarily enſue.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Secondly,</hi> The <hi>Wood-mongers</hi> having by the means be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore mentioned, ſo far prevailed, to obſtruct the Dealing of all
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:32945:5"/> others, and to obtain unto their own hands the ſole Trade of Coals, have uſed of late by confederacy (after they have compe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tently ſtored themſelves) to with-draw and abſent from the City ſeveral dayes, upon arrival of the <hi>Summer</hi> Coal-Fleet, retarding the ſame at dead Markets, in deſign to diſappoint a Voyage, and ſo upon pretence and colour of ſcarcity, to raiſe the Price afterwards at their own will. <hi>Whereas,</hi> If they gave the wonted quick diſpatch or diſcharge of ſuch Fleets, the ſame might, (as is credibly informed) make oftner returns for the ſtore and ſupply of the City.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Thirdly,</hi> They agree (as may beſt ſerve their turns) in <hi>Sum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer</hi> time, to lay aſide a Carr-room or more a peece, to promote a <hi>Winter</hi> Trade, by reſtraining and diſabling themſelves to ſerve out their Fuel in the <hi>Summer</hi> and cheapeſt time, that by pretence of over-much Work, they may deferr their Custo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mers to the later and dearer Seaſons of the Year; and if any happen to make timely and cheaper contracts, they often force them, notwithſtanding, to pay the Rates of the later or dearer Seaſon, which themſelves have choſe for delivery of the Coals.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Fourthly,</hi> It hath been further obſerved of the <hi>Wood-mongers,</hi> upon their late raiſing the Price of Coals, that there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon, they alſo raiſed and diſperſed a Report and rumour, that a price was about to be ſet by the Magiſtracy and Authority of this City, upon Sea-Coals, thereby to diſcourage and hinder the bringing in of any more Coals, till they had uttered their own Stores at the preſent dear or dearer Rates.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Secondly,</hi> Touching the <hi>Wood-mongers</hi> abuſes in the Meaſure and Weight of Coals, the ſame are evidenced in the following particulars.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Firſt,</hi> That they Buy by the juſt and Lawful Meaſures of this City, and Sell by the leſs and Unlawful Sacks, which are made by their own Order, Sized and Licenſed for Twelve pence a Sett, at their <hi>Common-Hall,</hi> and enjoyned (with
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:32945:5"/> a prohibition of the Coal-Meters) to be uſed by all the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany, whereby, and by other Artifices, they make Twenty three, and Twenty four Chaldron of a Score. And if by the Coal-Meters means, or any omiſſion, or unskilfulneſs of their own Servants, they are diſappointed of thoſe unjuſt advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tages, they fall upon them with evil and reviling Language, as the Authors of ſome unuſual and great injury to them.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Secondly,</hi> If any go about to Meaſure their ſaid unlawful Sacks, (which generally want three or four Buſhels in a Chaldron) the Carr-men, if they diſcover the Meters, will, to avoid them, drive away, and rather go far about, and carry back their Coals, than ſubject them to be Meaſured. And the <hi>Wood-mongers</hi> do give notice and an ill Character of ſuch perſon in their Company, that all may beware or avoid to ſerve him with Coals for the future.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Thirdly,</hi> They practice alike, or greater deceipt in the Weight of Pitt Coals, which by ſome have been diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered to Sell under Weight above Four hundred, and ſometimes Six hundred in a Tunn.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Fourthly,</hi> they allure by Compoſitions and deter by vexa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tious Actions, and Arreſts, ſuch as are imployed, or go about to proſecute any <hi>Wood-monger</hi> for deceipt in the Weight or Meaſure of their Coals.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>And</hi> no leſs are their abuſes (as is likewiſe atteſted) in the Buying and Selling of Wood, which contrary to Law, and many good Acts of <hi>Common-Council,</hi> they uſually for their greater gain, go down and deal for in the Country, allowing it to be Cut and made up under aſſize, conditioning to abate in Price for the ſame accordingly; inſomuch, that the Billets which they Buy at Eleven or Twelve Shillings, they Sell again for Two and twenty Shillings a Thouſand: Whereas no Fire-Wood ought to be Bought by the <hi>Wood-mongers,</hi> till it be brought up to the City and viewed, and found to be of good aſſize, and the Price ſet thereon by the Lord Mayor, and that
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:32945:6"/> it have lain upon the Water in <hi>Winter</hi> Eight Hours, and in <hi>Summer</hi> Twelve hours, for any Citizen or Private Perſon to furniſh for their own uſe.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>It</hi> is further complained and very evident, that there being about Fifty of the Number of Carr-men of the Poorer ſort, who had Carr-rooms, and were called Pentioners to the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany of <hi>Wood-mongers,</hi> the ſaid Company deſigning to ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance a Sum of Money for their common uſe upon the ſaid poor Men, did propoſe to them either to take Twenty Pounds a peece, and reſign their ſaid Carr-rooms, or to give and pay ſo much to the ſaid Company and retain them, and did thereupon inforce the ſaid poor Men to raiſe and pay Twenty Pounds a peece, (amounting in all to a Thouſand Pounds, or thereabouts) to continue the benefit of their ſaid Carr-rooms, which many of them were very unable to do, being in want before, for the relief and livelihood of themſelves and their Families.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Now,</hi> for remedy of the before mentioned Evils and Abuſes of the <hi>Wood-mongers;</hi> and Firſt, of inhancing the price of Sea-Coal, <hi>We think fit,</hi>
                           </p>
                           <p>☞ <hi>1.</hi> That the <hi>Act of Common-Council,</hi> made the Tenth of <hi>May,</hi> in the Year <hi>1661.</hi> whereby the ſaid Company are reinveſted with the Government of Carrs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and the Number limitted to Four Hundred and twenty, and of them One hundred and forty aſſigned to the Wharfs, for Carriage of Fuel, and by means of which Act, the <hi>Wood-mongers</hi> (as is conceived) do aſſume the power and advantages of thoſe practices, be repealed, or ſo altered, that the whole Number of Carrs may be at liberty (as they were before) for the Carriage of Coals and other Fuel; And that it may not be in the <hi>Wood-mongers</hi> power to hinder, but that all that will may Buy, either for their own uſe, or to Sell again, and have free liberty to Land, Un-load, and Meaſure their Coals at any common Wharfs and Keys, or other convenient places, and Carts to carry them home at their own pleaſure.</p>
                           <pb n="9" facs="tcp:32945:6"/>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Secondly,</hi> That there be ſome conſiderable ſtock of Coals, (by ſuch means as this Court ſhall think ſit) provided yearly, (as hath been formerly intended) at the cheapeſt, and ſold out at the deareſt Seaſons of the Year, to keep down the Price upon any emergent occaſion, eſpecially for the help and relief of the Poor.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Thirdly,</hi> That when it is found expedient a Price be ſet upon Coals, according to the Cuſtom of the City.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Secondly,</hi> To prevent the ſaid deceits in falſe Meaſures, and Weight of Coals, <hi>We think fit,</hi>
                           </p>
                           <p>☞ <hi>Firſt,</hi> That the <hi>Wood-mongers</hi> be not permitted to keep any Carrs to their Wharfs, but that all be Street Carrs, and imployed for the Carriage of Fuel as for any other Work.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Secondly,</hi> That the <hi>Wood-mongers,</hi> and all other Traders on Sea-Coals, be ſtrictly held for time to come, not to ſend abroad any Coals Sold or Contracted for, in any Sacks, other than the Sea-Coal-Meters, and to carry along in their Carts a Lawful Sealed Buſhel, Nineteen Inches in Breadth, and Seven Inches and a half in Depth, (and that like Sealed Buſhells be kept in every Pariſh) for every Buyer that will, to Meaſure his own Coals as they are brought home, as in and by an Act of Common-Council, made the Seventh of <hi>September, 1632.</hi> and many former and other good Acts and Orders is more fully enjoyned and directed.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Thirdly,</hi> That for avoiding deceit in the Weight in Pit-Coals, every Buyer may uſe a Meter, who upon Requeſt, is to attend to Weigh the Coals at the Buying, or bringing home of the ſame.</p>
                           <p>
                              <hi>And laſtly,</hi> To remedy the falſe Size and high Price of Wood, We conceive the ſame cannot be better effected, than by executing the Acts and Laws in force, which expoſe all Billets and Faggots under Size to be Seized, and Forfeited, and do forbid the Sale of any Fire-wood to the <hi>Wood-mongers</hi> and Retailers, till the ſame be brought to ſuch Key as the Lord
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:32945:7"/> Mayor ſhall appoint, and have lain upon the Water Eight Hours in <hi>Winter,</hi> and Twelve in the <hi>Summer,</hi> for private Perſons to furniſh themſelves, and that the Lord Mayor have ſet thereupon a Price, (as was heretofore uſed to be done) to be kept and obſerved under ſevere Penalties and Forfeitures.</p>
                           <closer>
                              <signed>And ſo We humbly ſubmit the Premiſes to the better Judgement and Conſideration of this Honou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable Court,</signed>
                              <date>
                                 <hi>this</hi> 14th <hi>day of</hi> February, <hi>1664.</hi>
                              </date>
                           </closer>
                        </div>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
               </q>
               <p>
                  <hi>Upon Reading whereof, as alſo of a Petition of the Maſter, Wardens, and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Company, and of ſome overtures touching the Surrendring up the Leaſe made to the ſaid Company, and of the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of Carrs and Carr-men within this City and Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties; this Court doth defer their further proceedings thereupon till the ſaid Company ſhall give their Anſwer touching the Surrendring up the ſaid Leaſe.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="11" facs="tcp:32945:7"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>LAWRENCE MAYOR.</hi> Com. Concil. tent. Decimo ſeptimo die <hi>Februarii,</hi> Anno Dom. <hi>1664.</hi> Anno Regni Regis <hi>CAROLI</hi> II. nunc Angliae, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Decimo ſeptimo.</head>
               <p>AT this Court, the Maſter and Wardens of the Company of <hi>Wood-mongers</hi> did ſurrender up the Leaſe made unto the ſaid Company, under the Common Seal of this City, in the time of the Mayoralty of Sir <hi>Richard Brown,</hi> Knight and Baronet, touching the Government of Carrs, Carr-men, and Carr-rooms, and the counterpart of the ſame Leaſe, Sealed to the City, was delivered up unto the Maſter and Wardens, and a Bond, under the Common Seal of the ſaid Company, for the payment of One hundred and fifty Pounds <hi>per annum</hi> to the uſe of <hi>Christs-Hoſpital,</hi> for the term of Sixty and one Years in the ſame Leaſe con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained, and lately remaining in the Chamber of <hi>London,</hi> not being to be found for the preſent, a Releaſe of the ſame Bond under the Common Seal of this City was Read and Sealed in open Court, the tenor whereof followeth.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whereas,</hi> the late Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the Fellowſhip of <hi>Wood-mongers, London,</hi> have by their Obligation under the Common Seal of the ſaid Corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration, bearing Date the Twenty third day of <hi>July,</hi> in the Thirteenth year of the Reign of Our Soveraign Lord <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, by the Grace of God of <hi>England, Scotland, France,</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> King, Defender of the Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Bound themſelves and their Succeſſors to the Mayor, Commonalty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> in the Sum or penalty of One Thouſand Pounds, with
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:32945:8"/> condition thereon Endorſed, for the true and ſure Payment of the Sum of One hundred and fifty Pounds yearly, and every year during the term of Sixty one years, from the Twenty fourth day of <hi>June</hi> then laſt paſt, at two ſeveral Payments, by even and equal portions, that is to ſay, At the Feaſt of the Birth of our Lord, Seventy five Pounds, and at the Feaſt of St. <hi>John Baptiſt,</hi> Seventy five Pounds, or within 40 daies after each of the ſaid Feaſt daies, to the Treaſurer of <hi>Christ-Hoſpital,</hi> for the time be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, for the maintenance of the poor Children therein harboured, as in and by the ſaid Obligation and Condi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, could the ſame be produced, more fully and plainly may appear.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Now know all men by theſe preſents,</hi> That the Mayor, Commonalty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> for divers good cauſes and conſiderations hereunto moving, have remiſed, releaſed, cleared, and quit-claimed, and by theſe Preſents for them and their Succeſſors, fully, clearly, and abſolutely Remiſe, Releaſe, and for ever quit-claim unto the Maſter, Wardens, and Aſſiſtants, of the Fellowſhip of <hi>Wood-mongers,</hi> and their Succeſſors, the aforeſaid Obligation and Condition thereof, and all and all manner of Actions, and Cauſes of Actions, Plaints, Proceſs, Suits and Demands whatſoever, which the ſaid Mayor, Commonalty, and Citizens, againſt the ſaid Maſter, Wardens, and Aſſiſtants, or their Succeſſors ever had, now have, or at any time hereafter may or might have, by reaſon or means of the ſaid Obligations and Conditions thereof in any wiſe howſoever.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>In witneſs whereof,</hi> The ſaid Mayor, Commonalty, and Citizens, have cauſed their Common Seal to be put to theſe Preſents, Dated the Seventeenth day of <hi>February, Anno Dom.</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundred Sixty and Four, in the Seventeenth year of the Reign of Our Soveraign
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:32945:8"/> Lord, <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, by the Grace of God of <hi>England, Scotland, France,</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> King, Defender of the Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And</hi> it was Reſolved that the thanks of this Court be returned to the Right Honourable the Lord Mayor, and alſo to Sir <hi>William Turner,</hi> Knight and Alderman, and the reſt of the Committee appointed by this Court, for the management of the aforeſaid affair, for their great care and pains taken therein.</p>
               <div type="section">
                  <p>UPon this Report, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> The Government of the Carrs was taken from the Company of <hi>Wood-mongers;</hi> And by Act of <hi>Common-Council,</hi> bearing Date the Twenty firſt day of <hi>June, 1665.</hi> were placed in the Preſident and Governors of <hi>Chriſt-Hoſpital,</hi> and by that Act amongſt other things is as followeth.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>And</hi> for the prevention of ſuch Deceipt hereafter, as di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers <hi>Wood-mongers</hi> have Practiſed in the Sale and Mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure of their Coals, <hi>It is Enacted,</hi> That all Sea-Coals here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after to be Sold, or Uttered by Retail, by any Perſon or Perſons whatſoever, ſhall be filled and brought home to the Buyers in the Sea-Coal-Meeters Sacks, or ſuch other Sacks as contain the full Meaſure of the Sea-Coal-Meters Sacks, and are and ſhall be Marked by the Keeper of the <hi>Guild-Hall</hi> for the time being, according to an Order of the Court of Aldermen, made the Twenty fifth day of <hi>October,</hi> in the time of the Mayo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ralty of Sir <hi>Thomas Cambell,</hi> Knight, deceaſed, and carried by ſome Street Carr or Carrs, of Perſons duly Licenſed and Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed as aforeſaid, and bearing upon the ſame Carrs the Mark of the <hi>Red-Croſs,</hi> for a Note of their Allowance, as hath antiently been accuſtomed.</p>
                  <pb n="14" facs="tcp:32945:9"/>
                  <p>
                     <hi>The</hi> Governours of <hi>Chriſt-Hoſpital,</hi> together with the Fellowſhip of Carr-Men, have been at great Charges in Suits of Law, to bring the ſaid <hi>Wood-mongers</hi> or Retailers in Fuel to a compliance with the ſaid Act of <hi>Common-Council;</hi> They with their Purſes and Perſons, have in all Courts oppoſed the ſame, ſome of them well knowing, that if the Carr-men ſhould be permitted to carry Fuel, they ſhould loſe great ſums of Money yearly, which they now get by the delivery of ſhort Meaſure, and ſeveral of them have been Indicted at Seſſions for delivering ſometimes two Buſhels, and ſometimes three Buſhels ſhort in a Load of Coals.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>The</hi> Argument about this by Law in the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> and at the <hi>Kings-Bench-Bar</hi> have not been yet determined, by reaſon ſome few things ſhould be added to them by Law, which the Governours do earneſtly pray the <hi>Common-Council</hi> to do.</p>
                  <p>The Honourable Houſe of <hi>Commons, January</hi> the 29th, <hi>1673.</hi> Ordered, That a Bill ſhould be prepared by a Committee then named, for the Regulating and Aſcertaining the Meaſure of Coals, and Abuſes in the Sale of Wood.</p>
                  <p>The Sixteenth of <hi>February, 1673.</hi> The Committee Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ports, They had prepared a Bill, and delivered it in, which was Read, and Ordered a ſecond Reading.</p>
                  <p>The Twenty fourth of <hi>February, 1673.</hi> The Parliament was Prorogued, ſo that the Bill received no further debate at that time.</p>
                  <p>The Sixth of <hi>March, 1673/4.</hi> His Majeſty was Graciouſly pleaſed to ſend to the City this Letter following.</p>
                  <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
                     <body>
                        <pb n="15" facs="tcp:32945:9"/>
                        <head>Charles R.</head>
                        <p>TRuſty and Well-beloved, We Greet you well; Whereas We are given to under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtand, That in this laſt Seſſion of <hi>Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,</hi> by Order of the Houſe of <hi>Commons,</hi> a Bill was prepared and Read, for the Regulating Abuſes in the Meaſure of Coal and Wood, within that Our City of <hi>London,</hi> Borough of <hi>Southwark,</hi> Liberties of the Tower of <hi>London,</hi> St. <hi>Katherines,</hi> and <hi>Eaſt-Smithfield,</hi> but the ſaid Bill not having been paſſed into an Act, by reaſon of the Prorogation, and the ſaid Abuſes ſtill continuing to the great Oppreſſion and Grie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance of Our good Subjects, We have thought fit hereby to recommend to you in an eſpecial Manner, the Regulation thereof, and as well the putting in Execution all Orders already made, for and towards the Redreſſing all Abuſes and Deceits of that kind, as the making ſuch Orders as may totally prevent the ſame for the future; Wherein We cannot doubt of your
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:32945:10"/> particular Care, and ſo We bid you Farewel. Given at Our Court at <hi>White-hall,</hi> this Sixth day of <hi>March,</hi> 1673/4. in the Twenty ſixth year of Our Reign.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>
                              <hi>By His Majeſties ſpecial Command,</hi> ARLINGTON.</signed>
                        </closer>
                        <trailer>
                           <hi>To Our Trusty and Well-beloved Sir</hi> William Hooker, <hi>Knight, Lord Mayor of Our City of</hi> LONDON, <hi>and to the Aldermen and Common-Council of that Our City.</hi>
                        </trailer>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="17" facs="tcp:32945:10"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>HOOKER MAYOR.</hi> Com. Concil. tent. in Camera <hi>Guild-hall</hi> Civit. <hi>Lond.</hi> die Martis decimo nono die <hi>Maii,</hi> Anno Dom. 1674. Annoque Regni Regis <hi>Caroli</hi> Secundi <hi>&amp;c.</hi> viceſſimo ſexto.</head>
               <p>AT this Court was Preſented and Read His Majeſties Letter, directed to this Court, Dated at <hi>White-hall,</hi> the Sixth day of <hi>March,</hi> laſt paſt, ſetting forth, That His Majeſty had been given to underſtand, that in the laſt Seſſion of Parliament, by Order of the Houſe of Commons, a Bill was prepared and read for the regulating the abuſes in the Meaſures of Coals and Wood within this City, Borough of <hi>Southwark,</hi> Liberties of the Tower of <hi>London,</hi> St. <hi>Katherines,</hi> and <hi>Eaſt-Smithfield;</hi> but the ſaid Bill, not paſſing into an Act, by reaſon of the Prorogation, and the ſame abuſes ſtill continuing, to the great oppreſſion and grievance of His Majeſties Subjects: Therefore His Majeſty was Graciouſly pleaſed by his ſaid Letter, to recommend to this Court in eſpecial manner the regulating thereof: And as well the putting in execution all Orders already made, for and towards the redreſſing all Abuſes and Deceits of that kind, as the making ſuch Orders as may totally prevent the ſame for the future; This Court in Obedience to the ſaid Command, doth nominate and appoint Sir <hi>John Frederick,</hi> Sir <hi>William Turner,</hi> Sir <hi>Richard Ford,</hi> Sir <hi>John Moore,</hi> Knights Aldermen, Sir <hi>Robert Jeoffories,</hi> and Sir <hi>Thomas Player,</hi> Knights, <hi>William Fluellin</hi> Eſq; Mr. <hi>Pilkington,</hi> Mr. <hi>Tompſon,</hi> Major <hi>Gunſton,</hi> Mr. <hi>Short,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Turgis</hi>
                  <pb n="18" facs="tcp:32945:11"/> Commoners, or any Two of the ſaid Aldermen, and Four of the ſaid Commoners, to be a Committee, forthwith to meet and conſult what is fit to be done, for redreſſing the ſame Abuſes, and Report their Opinions therein to this Court, and <hi>William Bird</hi> to Warn and Attend them.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Wagſtaffe.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="19" facs="tcp:32945:11"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>PEAKE MAYOR. Martis</hi> 28. die <hi>April.</hi> 1668. Annoque Regni Regis CAROLI Secundi Angliae, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> XX.</head>
               <p>THis day the Preſident and Governours of <hi>Chriſts-Hoſpital, London,</hi> to whom the Rule, Over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſight and Government of Carrs, Carts, Carr-rooms, Carters and Carmen, within the City of <hi>London,</hi> and Liberties thereof, is committed by Act of <hi>Common-Council,</hi> made the One and twentieth day of <hi>June,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundred Sixty Five, in the Seventeenth Year of His Majeſties Reign, exhibited into this Court a Book of Orders, Rules, Directions, and Limitations, deviſed for the better Regulation of the ſaid Carrs, Carts, Carters, and Carr-men, Humbly ſubmitting the ſame to be allowed and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmed by this Court, according to the ſaid Act of <hi>Common-Council,</hi> and the Cuſtom of this City; Whereupon the ſaid Orders, Rules, Directions, and Limitations were here openly and deliberately read, and adviſedly and maturely conſidered, and after ſome alterations and amendments there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in made, were well liked, ratified and confirmed, and Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered to be obſerved, executed and performed by all Perſons concerned in all Points, and in all times hereafter, until this Court, or the <hi>Common-Council</hi> of this City ſhall ſee cauſe to Order or Direct any thing to the contrary thereof, or of any Articles or Clauſes therein contained.</p>
               <pb n="20" facs="tcp:32945:12"/>
               <p>
                  <hi>And it is further Ordered,</hi> That the ſaid Preſident and Governours may as they ſee cauſe, uſe and publiſh the ſaid Orders, Rules, Directions, and Limitations, under the Title, and in manner and form following; That is to ſay,</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>ORDERS, R<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>LES, DIRECTIONS,</hi> and <hi>LIMITATIONS,</hi> Made by the Right Honourable Sir <hi>William Peake,</hi> Knight, Lord Mayor of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and the Right Worſhipful the Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dermen his Brethren, at a Court held in the Chamber of the <hi>Guild-Hall, London,</hi> on <hi>Tueſday,</hi> the Eight and Twentieth day of <hi>April,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundred Sixty and Eight, in the Twentieth Year of the Reign of Our Soveraign Lord King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> for the further Direction of the Preſident and Governours of <hi>Chriſts-Hoſpital, London,</hi> in the Rule, Overſight, and Government of the Carrs, Carts, Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters, and Carmen, within the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> and Liberties thereof, and for the better Government and Ordering of the ſaid Carrs, Carts, Carters, and Carmen, within the ſaid City of <hi>London,</hi> in purſuance of an Act of <hi>Common-Council,</hi> held in the Chamber of the <hi>Guild-hall</hi> of the ſaid City,
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:32945:12"/> the One and Twentieth day of <hi>June,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundred Sixty and Five, and in the Seventeenth Year of His ſaid Majeſties Reign.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>WHereas</hi> heretofore (that is to ſay) in the Third Year of the Reign of Our late Soveraign Lord King <hi>James,</hi> of <hi>England,</hi> &amp;c. (and of <hi>Scotland,</hi> the Nine and Thirtieth) the Carr-Men of <hi>London</hi> were Incorporated with the Company of <hi>Wood-mongers, London,</hi> by His ſaid Highneſs Letters Patents bearing date the Nine and Twentieth day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> in the Years aforeſaid, ſince which time (to wit) the Fifth day of <hi>December,</hi> in the Nineteenth Year of the Reign of Our now Soveraign Lord King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, the Maſter and Wardens of the ſaid Company of <hi>Wood-mongers,</hi> by their Writing under their Common Seal, and by them ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knowledged in <hi>Chancery,</hi> did ſurrender to Our now Sove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raign Lord the King the ſaid Letters Patents, and by means thereof, are Diſincorporated, by reaſon whereof, the ſaid Carr-men have humbly beſought this Court, that they may be a Fellowſhip, or Fraternity, as anciently, and ſuch Orders made by this Court for the better Regulating and Ordering the ſeveral Members of the ſaid Fellowſhip, as ſhould be thought expedient.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>This</hi> Court well weighing the deſire of the ſaid Carr-men, and conſidering, that the Mayor, and Commonalty, and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of this City, time out of mind, have had the right of Ordering and diſpoſing of Carrs, Carts, Carr-rooms, Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters, and Carr-men, and of all other perſon or perſons what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever, Working any Carr or Carts within the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> and Liberties thereof; And in purſuance thereof, by the ſaid Act of <hi>Common Council,</hi> made the One and twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tieth
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:32945:13"/> day of <hi>June,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundred Sixty and Five, have placed the Rule, Overſight, and Government of them, in the Preſident and Governours of <hi>Chriſt-Hoſpital, London,</hi> to Order them according to the Rules, Directions, and Proviſions in the ſaid Act mentioned, and according to ſuch other Orders, Rules, Directions, and Limitations, as the ſaid <hi>Common Council</hi> or this Court, upon conſideration, ſhould make and provide in that behalf. And further conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dering, that the ſaid Act doth not ſufficiently provide for the Ordering and Regulating ſuch Perſons as ſhould be Members of the ſaid Fellowſhip in their labours,</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Have</hi> therefore thought it fit and neceſſary, to declare how and in what manner the ſaid Carr-men ſhall be governed for the future, under the ſaid Preſident and Governours, and what Orders and Rules they ſhall put in execution amongſt themſelves.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And Firſt,</hi> This Court doth deſire the ſaid Preſident, or Governours, ſtrictly to obſerve, and effectually to put in exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution all ſuch Orders, Rules, Directions, and Limitations, as are mentioned and contained in the ſaid Act of <hi>Common Council,</hi> of the One and Twentieth of <hi>June,</hi> One Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Six Hundred Sixty and Five, which concerneth the Rule, Overſight, and Government of the ſaid Carr-men, and other Perſons, working Carrs, and Carts, in the ſaid Act of <hi>Common-Council</hi> mentioned.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Secondly,</hi> That the ſaid Preſident or Governours ſtrictly obſerve and effectually put in Execution all the Orders, Rules, Directions, and Limitations, mentioned in an Order of the General Quarter Seſſions, holden at <hi>Juſtice-Hall</hi> in the <hi>Old Bayley,</hi> the Sixteenth day of <hi>January,</hi> in the Eigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth Year of the Reign of Our Soveraign Lord King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> which Order of Seſſions doth not only ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point what Rates the ſaid Carr-men ſhall receive, but doth give further Directions how the ſaid Carr-men ſhall be Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:32945:13"/> by the ſaid Preſident or Governours for the future. And the ſaid Preſident or Governours, are not only deſired to obſerve the ſaid Act of <hi>Common-Council,</hi> and Order of Seſſions, and the Orders hereafter following, but alſo all other Acts of <hi>Common-Council,</hi> Orders of this Court and Court of Seſſions, as ſhall hereafter be made concerning the ſaid Carr-men.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Thirdly,</hi> The ſaid Preſident or Governours are deſired by this Court, to take care, that every Cart allowed by them to Work within the City of <hi>London,</hi> and the Liberties thereof, contain in length between the <hi>Tugg-hole</hi> and the <hi>Fore-Ear</hi> breadth Six Foot and Four Inches of Aſſize and no more, and in breadth, between the two <hi>Raves</hi> in the Body of the ſaid Cart, four Foot of Aſſize, and no more; and in length, from the <hi>Fore-Ear</hi> breadth to the end of the Cart, ſeven Foot and two Inches of Aſſize, and no more; And if any Carr ſhall be found of greater Length or Breadth, that then the ſame Carr, may be taken up by the ſaid Preſident or Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nours, or their Officer or Officers, appointed for that purpoſe, and be ſent to the New Store-Yard.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Fourthly,</hi> The ſaid Preſident or Governours are deſired to take care that all Carr-men be Ordered with their empty Carrs to ſtand in convenient places of this City, to be ready for Merchants and all other Perſons that ſhall have occaſions to uſe them. And if any Carr-man ſhall not obſerve the Rule that ſhall be made by the ſaid Preſident or Governours, for their standings in the Streets for Merchants and others, every Carr-man ſo offending, ſhall for the firſt Offence, pay Two Shillings and Six pence, for the ſecond Offence Five Shillings, and for his third, and every other Offence, Ten Shillings; And for refuſal or not payment of any of the ſaid Fines, they to be by the ſaid Preſident or Governours diſcharged from Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king any Carr or Cart within the City of <hi>London,</hi> and Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties thereof.</p>
               <pb n="24" facs="tcp:32945:14"/>
               <p>
                  <hi>Fifthly,</hi> That the ſaid Preſident or Governours ſhall take care, that no Carr-man leave his Carr in the Streets, Lanes, or Common Paſſages of this City or Liberties thereof by Night, whereby any perſon or perſons may take harm, upon pain of Forfeiting for every time he or they ſo leave his Carr in the Streets by Night, the ſum of Five Shillings, beſides recompence to the party as ſhall ſuſtain hurt or damage thereby.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Sixthly,</hi> That the ſaid Preſident or Governours take care, that no Carr within this City be heard to creak, or pipe for dryneſs, or want of Greaſing in the <hi>Nave,</hi> and every Owner of ſuch Carr as ſhall be found ſo to do, ſhall Forfeit and Pay for every day that his Carr ſhall be obſerved to creak, or pipe; the ſum of Two Shillings.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Seventhly,</hi> That the ſaid Preſident or Governours take care that no Carr-man, within this City or Liberties thereof uſe or put into his Carr for the carriage of any Merchandiſe whatſoever, any more Horſes, than One at one time, except it be up the Hill, or with Timber or Stone that cannot be divided, upon pain of Forfeiting for every Offence, Two Shillings.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Eighthly,</hi> That the ſaid Preſident or Governours take care, that no perſon or perſons ſhall take up or carry greater Loads than was the ancient cuſtom or practice to do, which ancient cuſtom or practice ſhall be declared by the ſaid Preſident or Governours to all the Carr-men, upon pain, that every per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon that ſhall ſo do, ſhall Forfeit and pay the ſum of Five Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings for the first Offence, the ſecond Offence Ten Shillings, and for the third offence, ſhall be diſenabled from further Working a Carr, within the City of <hi>London,</hi> and Liberties thereof.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Ninthly,</hi> That the ſaid Preſident or Governours take care that no Carr-man, his Journey-man, or Servant ride upon his Carr, or drives his Horſe a Trot in the Street, or otherwiſe, in a more ſpeedy courſe or pace than is uſual, upon pain of
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:32945:14"/> Forfeiting for every Offence herein, Two Shillings.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Tenthly,</hi> That the ſaid Preſident, or Governours take care, that every Carr-man lead his Horſe by the Head, with an Horſe Halter of three Foot and no longer, with a ſpecial regard alwayes before him as behind him, as well for Children as for Aged people; and if he ſhall ſuffer his Horſe to go in the Streets without leading him, as aforeſaid, for every time he ſhall ſo offend, he ſhall forfeit and pay Two Shillings.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Eleventhly,</hi> That the ſaid Preſident, or Governours take care, that no Carr-man within this City and Liberties thereof, ſhall appoint any Servant, or Journey man to go with any Carr, or Cart, before he be preſented to them the ſaid Preſident, or Governours, and allowed by them, which Servant or Jour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neyman ſhall be of the age of Eighteen Years, at the leaſt; and whatſoever Carr-man ſhall hereafter entertain and imploy as a Carr-man, in guiding of a Carr, any ſuch Servant the full time of ſix Weeks before he be preſented to the ſaid Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſident or Governours, then he ſhall forfeit and pay for every Week that he ſhall ſo entertain and keep him before ſuch pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſentment, the ſum of Five Shillings, and that all the now Servants of Carr-men ſhall appear before the ſaid Preſident or Governours with their Indentures, to be Allowed and En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tred in the Books of the ſaid Governours, for which Entrance to pay Six Pence.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Twelfthly,</hi> Further, that if any Maſter Carr-man, or any other, uſing or enjoying a Carr within this City and Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties thereof, ſhall put away, or ſett over his Servant or Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants ſo preſented to the ſaid Preſident or Governours, or ſhall bargain, or ſett over any year or years of any ſuch Servant or Servants, or any other perſon or perſons, before ſuch Carr-man hath firſt obtained and gotten the good will and conſent of the Preſident or Governours aforeſaid for the time being, ſo to do, that it may appear by their Regiſter Book kept by the ſaid Preſident or Governours, of the honeſt and lawful departure,
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:32945:15"/> putting away, or ſetting over of every ſuch Servant or Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants, that then he the ſaid Maſter Carr-man ſhall for every Offence to the contrary, pay Six Shillings and Eight Pence.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Thirteenthly,</hi> Further, that the ſaid Preſident or Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nours take care, that no Carr-man within the City of <hi>London</hi> and Liberties thereof, have more than one Apprentice at one time, and one Journeyman; and if it ſhall appear to the ſaid Preſident or Governours, that the ſaid Carr-man hath any more than one Apprentice and Journeyman, then the ſaid Carr-man to loſe his admittance of Working any Carr or Cart within <hi>London,</hi> and the Liberties thereof.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Fourteenthly,</hi> Further, the ſaid Preſident or Governours are deſired, that when any Servant or Journeyman is preſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to them to be allowed, and approved to Work a Carr or Cart in <hi>London,</hi> and the Liberties thereof, then they to declare to the ſaid Servant or Journeyman, that the ſole diſpoſing of all Carrs to Work, is in the Mayor, and Commonalty, and Citizens of <hi>London,</hi> and in ſuch as claim by, from, or under them, and that he cannot have any Cart to Work or Hire, till one falls void, although he hath ſerved the term of Seven Years Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentiſhip.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Fifteenthly,</hi> Further, the ſaid Preſident or Governours are deſired to take care, that no ſuch Servant or Servants, do at any time hereafter, mis-behave him or themſeves in the Street, and if any be found ſo to do, then they to inflict ſuch Puniſhment upon ſuch Servants for ſuch their Mis-behavi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ours, as in their diſcretion ſhall be thought fit; And if any Free-Carr-man ſhall mis-behave himſelf in the Streets, and proof thereof be made before the ſaid Preſident or Governours, he the ſaid Free-man, ſhall for his firſt Offence, pay Ten Shillings, and for his ſecond Offence Twenty Shillings, and for his third Offence Forty Shillings; And for refuſal of not paying of any of the ſaid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ines, to be diſcharged from Working any Carr within the City of <hi>London,</hi> and Liberties thereof.</p>
               <pb n="27" facs="tcp:32945:15" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <p>
                  <hi>Sixteenthly,</hi> The ſaid Preſident and Governours are de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſired not to admit any Perſon or Perſons to work a Carr within the City of <hi>London</hi> and Liberties thereof to their own uſe, other then ſuch as have ſerved Seven years Apprentiſhip to the calling, and hath a good teſtimony of his honeſt life and converſation.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Seventeenthly,</hi> And further the ſaid Preſident or Governours are deſired by this Court, To call all ſuch Carr-men before them as they ſhall admit or allow of, four times in every year yearly, or as often as they ſhall think fit; and to cauſe all the Orders that are now made, or ſhall hereafter be made for the Rule, Overſight, and Government of the ſaid Carrmen to be openly read to them. And if any Carr-man ſhall refuſe at any time or times to appear upon the Sum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons of the ſaid Preſident or Governours, by any of the four Street-men, or other Officers of the ſaid Preſident or Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nours then they to lay ſuch Fine, Penalty, or Suſpenſion, upon every ſuch Carr-man ſo offending, as in their diſcretion ſhall be thought moſt fit.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>All which</hi> Orders before mentioned ſhall be put in Execution by the Preſident or Governours of the ſaid Hoſpital: And by no other Perſon or Perſons whatſoever. And all the Fines ariſing by breach of the ſaid Ordinances, be applyed <hi>viz.</hi> One Moyety to the relief of the poor Children harboured in the ſaid <hi>Chriſts-Hoſpital:</hi> And the other Moyety to the Uſe of the Fellowſhip or Brotherhood of Carr-men.</p>
               <div type="orders">
                  <head>Now followeth the ORDERS for the <hi>FELLOWSHIP.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Firſt,</hi> That all manner of Perſons, who now are, or hereafter ſhall be duly allowed by the ſaid Preſident or Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nours of the ſaid Hoſpital, to work any Carr or Carts within
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:32945:16" rendition="simple:additions"/> the City of <hi>London,</hi> and Liberties thereof, ſhall be a Fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowſhip, and Fraternity by the name of the Carr-men of the City of <hi>London,</hi> to put in execution theſe Orders following, and no other. <hi>viz.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Secondly,</hi> That there ſhall be Three of the ſaid Fellow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip, in manner and form following, in theſe Preſents here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>under mentioned, choſen and named, which ſhall be, and be called the Wardens of the ſaid Fellowſhip of Carr-men of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don.</hi> And that it ſhall and may be lawful to and for the ſaid Members of the ſaid Brotherhood or Fellowſhip, within ſome convenient time, to Chooſe and Elect out of themſelves, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hree able and ſufficient Perſons, uſeing the Occupation of a Carr-man, to be Wardens of the ſaid Brotherhood or Fellowſhip, the ſpace of one whole year then next following, and from thence until a New Election be made. And that the ſame Three Perſons ſo Choſen to be Wardens, ſhall within convenient time after their ſaid Election be preſented, by a convenient number of the ſaid Brotherhood, in the Utter Court holden before the Lord Mayor, and Aldermen of the ſaid City, to be Sworn for the true execution of ſuch things as ſhall apper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain unto their Office, according to the good Rules and Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nances to them, to be allowed and approved by the ſame Court. And that it ſhall and may be lawful to and for the ſaid War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens ſo Sworn as aforeſaid, to call unto their Aſſiſtance, the number of Twenty of the Members of the ſaid Fellowſhip, who ſhall be, and be called the Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Fellow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Thirdly,</hi> That <hi>John Hill, William Turner</hi> and <hi>John Earle</hi> be the Three firſt Wardens of the ſaid Fellowſhip or Fraternity, to continue for one whole year; and that <hi>William Standley, John Standford, James Rough-head, John Fox, Robert Hardy, Edward Oxlad, Anthony Brown, Iſaac Preſton, John Clark, Thomas Haynes, Thomas Smith, Thomas Hooker, John Cue, James Maw,
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:32945:16" rendition="simple:additions"/> Edward Benſon, John Caines, Alexander Sheppard, Edward Tucker, Edward Lucar</hi> and <hi>John Chitwel,</hi> ſhall be firſt Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Fellowſhip or Frater<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Fourthly,</hi> That the old Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Brotherhood, may lawfully between the five and twenti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth Day of <hi>March,</hi> and the four and twentieth Day of <hi>June</hi> in every year then next following, aſſemble themſelves to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether in ſome convenient place, by them to be provided, within the City of <hi>London,</hi> and there to chooſe and elect of themſelves out of the ſaid Aſſiſtants of the ſame Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therhood, Three able men that uſe the ſaid Occupation, to be Wardens of the ſaid Brotherhood for one whole year then next following, and ſo forth until Three others ſhall be elected and ſworn into the ſaid Office. And the ſame Three Wardens ſo choſen, within Twenty dayes then next following after their ſaid Election, ſhall be ſworn in the ſaid Court to be holden in the ſaid Utter Chamber of <hi>Guild-Hall,</hi> before the <hi>Lord Mayor</hi> and <hi>Aldermen</hi> for the time being, truly to do and execute ſuch things as ſhall appertain and belong to their Office, according to the good Rules and Ordinances to them to be allowed and approved by the ſame Court. And that if the ſaid Wardens, being thus Elected and Sworn, happen to die within the ſaid Year that they ſhould ſtand Wardens, That then the Members of the ſaid Brotherhood, <hi>viz.</hi> the ſaid Wardens ſurviving, and the Aſſiſtants of the Brother<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood, may chuſe ſo many more of the ſame Occupation, to ſupply and ſerve in ſtead and place of him or them ſo deceaſed, for the reſidue of the ſaid Year, in form afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid. And in caſe any ſuch perſon or perſons refuſe to hold the ſaid place of a Warden, ſo choſen, the ſame per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on or perſons ſo refuſing, ſhall pay for a Fine, three Pounds, to be employed to the uſe of the ſaid Fellowſhip or Brother<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood.</p>
                  <pb n="30" facs="tcp:32945:17" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Fifthly,</hi> That within one Month next after the chu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing of the new Wardens, at the end of every Year in form aforeſaid, the old Wardens which occupied and ſtood in the Office, in the Year then next preceding, ſhall make and yield up their Accompts to the Wardens then choſen, and to three or four other perſons of the ſaid Brotherhood, ſuch as the ſaid new Wardens ſhall appoint to take their Accompts; and ſhall truly anſwer, pay and deliver unto the ſaid new Wardens, to the uſe of the ſame Brotherhood, all that which ſhall be found to remain in their hands upon that Accompt, upon pain of five pounds to be paid to the uſe of the ſaid Fellowſhip. And if the ſaid Accompt be behind, and not given up, and payment of what ſhall be found to remain in their hands, made as aforeſaid, That the old Wardens ſo failing (ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept they have a reaſonable and lawful excuſe) ſhall pay for every Month, ſo long as their Accompts are not given up, and ſatisfaction made within one Month after the chuſing of the new Wardens, the Sum of five Pounds over and above the aforeſaid penalty of five Pounds for failure of the firſt Month, to be employed as aforeſaid.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Sixthly,</hi> That the ſaid Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Brotherhood or Fellowſhip, may have, chuſe or ordain one meet perſon, fit and able, to be their Clerk; and one other fit perſon, or more than one, to be their Beadle or Beadles, as their common Officers, to make Summons in the name of the Wardens for the time being; and to execute other the lawful Precepts and Commandments of the ſaid Fellowſhip, as the Caſe ſhall require; the ſame Clerk and Beadle or Beadles to have ſuch Salary and Wages as the old Wardens and Brotherhood for the time being, ſhall think fit, and allow unto them; to be paid quarterly every Year. The ſame Beadle or Beadles to be of the Occupation aforeſaid: And that it ſhall be lawful for the ſaid Wardens for the time being, to Levy, Collect and Receive of the Members
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:32945:17" rendition="simple:additions"/> of the ſaid Brotherhood, a competent Sum of Money to be by them agreed upon, by the name of <hi>Quarteridge,</hi> towards the Charges of the ſaid Brotherhood, as in other Fellowſhips in this City is uſed; ſo as the ſame Quarteridge exceeds not Twelve pence a Quarter for any one perſon.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Seventhly,</hi> That as often as any perſon of the ſaid Brother<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood or Fellowſhip, hereafter ſhall be duly ſummoned by the Beadle of the ſaid Society, to appear before the Wardens of the ſaid Fellowſhip for the time being, at a certain hour aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigned, and appeareth not at the time and place appointed, according to their Summons, That the ſaid perſon ſo ſummon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, making default (unleſs he have ſome reaſonable and law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful excuſe) ſhall pay to the uſe of the ſaid Fellowſhip, for a Fine, ſuch a Sum of Money as the ſaid Wardens for the time being, ſhall appoint, not exceeding two Shillings and ſix<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pence.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Eighthly,</hi> That if any perſon, being a man of the ſame Fellowſhip, ſhall at any time hereafter, uſe, or give any evil, opprobrious or reviling Language in the Street, or elſewhere, to any other Free-man of the ſame Fellowſhip, that then the perſon ſo offending, ſhall pay to the uſe of the ſaid Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therhood, the Sum of five ſhillings. And if any Apprentice, Servant to any of the ſaid Fellowſhip, ſhall offend in ſuch wiſe, That then the ſame Apprentice or Servant ſhall be pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhed by the Order and Diſcretions of the Wardens of the ſaid Company for the time being.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Ninthly,</hi> That if any Free-man of the ſaid Fellowſhip, ſhall ſtrike, or fight with any of the ſaid Fellowſhip, that then he ſhall forfeit for every ſuch Offence, Ten Shillings, to be paid to the uſe of the ſaid Fellowſhip: And every Appren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice guilty of the like Offence, ſhall be puniſhed at the diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretion of the Wardens, as aforeſaid. But if any Free-man of the ſaid Fellowſhip, Journey-man or Servant, ſhall give evil, opprobrious or reviling Language in the Streets, or elſewhere,
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:32945:18" rendition="simple:additions"/> to any perſon whatſoever, not free of the ſaid Fellowſhip, or ſtrike, or fight with any ſuch perſon, the ſaid Brotherhood ſhall have nothing to do therein; but the ſaid Journeyman or Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant ſhall be puniſhed by the Order and Diſcretion of the Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſident or Governors of <hi>Chriſt's Hoſpital.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Tenthly,</hi> That for the preſervation of Unanimity and Brotherly Love amongst the ſaid Brotherhood, no perſon of the ſaid Fellowſhip whatſoever ſhall go to Suit of Law with any other Member of the ſame, for any Cauſe or Difference what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever, until he hath first acquainted the Wardens of the ſaid Company for the time being, therewith; and obtained Licenſe of them ſo to do. And if any of the ſaid Fellowſhip ſhall at any time offend herein, he ſhall forfeit and pay to the uſe of the ſaid Fellowſhip the Sum of Forty Shillings.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Eleventhly,</hi> That if any perſon of the ſaid Fellowſhip ſhall happen to forfeit any Sum or Sums of Money for any thing in theſe Orders, or any of them compriſed, and then the ſame perſon refuſe and deny to pay the ſame Money, it being two ſeveral times demanded, if the party offending be of abi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity, then the Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Fellowſhip ſhall complain to the <hi>Lord Mayor</hi> for the time being, and the perſon ſo offending is to be puniſhed after the diſcretion of the <hi>Lord Mayor</hi> and <hi>Court</hi> of <hi>Aldermen.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Twelfthly,</hi> That the Wardens of the ſaid Fellowſhip for the time being, ſhall not permit or ſuffer any Apprentice to be bound by them to any Free-man uſing the ſaid Occupation, until he do produce a Teſtimonial of Allowance from the ſaid Preſident or Governours, or whom they ſhall appoint.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Thirteenthly,</hi> That every perſon of the ſaid Brotherhood, within two Months after he taketh unto him any Apprentice, and hath the ſaid Teſtimonial of Allowance from the ſaid Preſident or Governours, or whom they ſhall appoint, ſhall preſent the ſame Apprentice to the Wardens of the ſaid Fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowſhip for the time being, and ſhall then pay unto the
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:32945:18" rendition="simple:additions"/> Common Box of the ſaid Fellowſhip, for the preſenting of eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry ſuch Apprentice the Sum of Twelve pence, and for the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denture Eighteen pence: And that none of the ſaid Brother<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood or Fellowſhip ſhall at any time hereafter, take an Appren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice for any ſhorter or leſſer time than Seven Years: And that ſuch Apprentice at the end of the ſaid Term, having truly ſerved his ſaid Term, ſhall be made free by his ſaid Maſter: And that ſuch Apprentice before his admittance into the Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of this City, ſhall be preſented again unto the Wardens of the ſaid Fellowſhip for the time being, and there before them, ſhall ſubſcribe a Note whereby he ſhall undertake to the Three Wardens to be contributary to all manner of Charges belonging to the ſaid Brotherhood to his power, and pay to the ſaid Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therhood for his admittance into the Brotherhood, Six Shillings and Eight pence, and to the Clerk Two Shillings and Six pence, and unto the Beadle Twelve pence.</p>
                  <q>
                     <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                        <body>
                           <div type="oath">
                              <head>The Oath of every Perſon at his firſt Admittance into the Brotherhood or Fellowſhip of CARR-MEN of the City of <hi>London;</hi> To be Adminiſtred by the Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Fellowſhip or Brotherhood for the time being.</head>
                              <p>
                                 <hi>YOu ſhall Swear,</hi> You ſhall be true to our Sove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raign Lord the King, and His Succeſſors; You ſhall be obedient to the Preſident or Governours of <hi>Chriſt's Hoſpital,</hi> and to ſuch in whom the City ſhall
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:32945:19" rendition="simple:additions"/> hereafter place the Government of Carrs, by the Act of <hi>Common-Council,</hi> and to the <hi>Wardens</hi> for the time preſent. You ſhall not diſcover the lawful Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſel of this Fraternity. You ſhall not take a Foreign man into your Service, but only ſuch as uſe the occu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pation of a Carr-man, or elſe an Apprentice duly bound without fraud; At the beginning of their Terms or before, you ſhall bring and preſent them before the <hi>Wardens</hi> of the ſaid Fellowſhip for the time being, and here have the Indentures to be made, and every ſuch Apprentice to be Inrolled within the firſt Year, as the Cuſtom is. You ſhall not entice or withdraw any mans Servant of this Society, until that reaſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nable departing be made with his ſaid Maſter.</p>
                              <p>Theſe, and all other good Rules made, and to be made not reverſed; You ſhall keep ſo near as God give you Grace.</p>
                              <closer>
                                 <signed>
                                    <hi>So help you God, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                                    </hi>
                                 </signed>
                              </closer>
                           </div>
                        </body>
                     </floatingText>
                  </q>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Fourteenthly,</hi> That no perſon being made a Free-man of the ſaid Brotherhood, ſhall take an Apprentice to be bound un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to him until he hath been a Free-man by the ſpace of four years (unleſs in caſe of Lameneſs and Sickneſs, and where a Journey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man of the ſaid Society is not to be had; and then the ſame to be with Licenſe of the Preſident or Governours of <hi>Chriſt's Hoſpital,</hi> and Wardens of the ſaid Fellowſhip for the time being) and after the expiration of the ſaid four years, then to take only one Apprentice and no more.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Fifteenthly,</hi> That if at any time, within the Term, any Wardens of the ſaid Brotherhood or Fellowſhip (which ſhall ſtand and occupy that Room) ſhall neglect to put in execution, and duly to obſerve theſe Orders and Rules in this Book to be kept according to the best of their power, and likewiſe to
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:32945:19"/> cauſe the ſame Ordinances to be read twice a Year in ſome con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venient place, to all the Fraternity and Brotherhood; that then the ſaid Wardens ſhall pay Twenty Shillings for a Fine in that behalf to the uſe of the ſaid Brotherhood.</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>
                        <hi>Pet. Concord. cum Original.</hi> AVERY.</signed>
                  </closer>
                  <postscript>
                     <p>And this Court doth Direct and Order, That Mr. <hi>Chamberlain</hi> ſhall take notice of the ſaid <hi>Carr-men</hi> as a <hi>Fellowſhip</hi> and <hi>Brotherhood</hi> of this City, and Enroll and make Free their Apprentices, according to the Intent and Meaning of the ſaid Ordinance.</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>AVERY.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </postscript>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="36" facs="tcp:32945:20"/>
               <head>The General Quarter-Seſſions have from time to time ſet Rates for the Carriage of all Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dities within the City of <hi>London</hi> and Liberties thereof, and added ſome other Rules to be obſerved by the Governours of <hi>Christs-Hoſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pital,</hi> and Fellowſhip of Carr-men, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as for inſtance: <hi>Ad General' Quarterial' Seſſion' Pacis Dom. Regis tent. pro Civitat'</hi> London, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>WHereas daily Complaints are made by Merchants and other Citizens and Inhabitants within the City of <hi>London</hi> and the Liberties thereof, of the exceſſive Rates demanded and received by Carr-men, above what is reaſonable and hath been limited and appointed for Carriages within this City and Liberties, and upon due conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration had, as well of former times as of the preſent, wherein ſeveral Materials of neceſſary and principal uſe to the Carr-men are riſen and conſequently require ſome increaſe of Rates heretofore ſet for their Labour and Carriage. Now the ſaid Juſtices of Peace here aſſembled reſpecting the times and other circumſtances neceſſary to be conſidered, do, by authority and virtue of the Statute in this caſe made and provided, order, limit, rate and appoint the Wages for Carr-men within the City of <hi>London</hi> and Liberties thereof, to be as hereafter followeth.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Firſt,</hi> That all Carr-men trading or working with Carrs in
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:32945:20"/> the City of <hi>London</hi> and Liberties thereof ſhall and may de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand and take for every Carriage or Load of the Commodities under-mentioned the Rates hereafter following, and ſhall not exceed the ſame upon pain to be ſtrictly puniſhed and proceeded againſt for every Offence to the contrary, That is to ſay,</p>
               <p>From any the Wharfs between the <hi>Tower</hi> and <hi>London<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bridge</hi> to <hi>Tower-ſtreet, Grace-Church-ſtreet, Fen-church-ſtreet, Biſhopſgate-ſtreet</hi> within, <hi>Corn-Hill,</hi> and places of like diſtance up the Hill, with eighteen hundred weight, not exceeding Twenty hundred Weight, Two Shillings two Pence.</p>
               <p>And being above Twenty hundred Weight, Two pence for every Hundred.</p>
               <p>Provided the Car-men for this Rate and all other Rates here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in contained, do help to load and unload their Carrs.</p>
               <p>In which may be included</p>
               <p>Two Puncheons of Prunes, two Bales of Mather, twenty Barrels of Figgs, two Fats of Fuſtians, ſix ordinary Sacks of Cotton-Woolls of <hi>Smyrna,</hi> and three <hi>Cyprus</hi> Bags, a Butt of Currans, a great Butt of Oyls, three Cheſts of Sugar, eight Bags of Alums, one Laſt of Flax, one Laſt of Hemp, and any other Goods herein not named of the like Weight; for every Load Two Shillings two Pence.</p>
               <p>And for Sea-coals the Load Fourteen Pence, every Load to be half a Chaldron; and for one hundred Faggots the like Rate.</p>
               <p>And from any the Wharfs aforeſaid to <hi>Broad-ſtreet, Loth-bury, Old-Jury, Baſſiſhaw, Coleman-ſtreet, Ironmonger-Lane,</hi> St. <hi>Laurence-Lane, Milk-ſtreet, Aldermanbury, Cheap-ſide, Wood-ſtreet, Friday-ſtreet, Bread-ſtreet,</hi> and places of like diſtance, for the like weight of Eighteen hundred, not exceeding Twenty hundred Weight, for the Goods aforeſaid, and other Goods herein not named of the like Weight; for every Load Two Shillings Six Pence.</p>
               <pb n="38" facs="tcp:32945:21"/>
               <p>And being above twenty Hundred Weight, upon every Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Two Pence.</p>
               <p>And for Sea-coals, the Load Sxteen Pence, every Load to be half a Chaldron; and for one hundred Faggots the like Rate.</p>
               <p>Alſo from any the Wharfs aforeſaid to <hi>Smithfield-Barrs, Holborn-Barrs, Temple-Barr,</hi> or any of the Barrs on the North-ſide of the City, and places of like diſtance up the Hill, with eighteen Hundred Weight, not exceeding twenty Hundred Weight; for every Load three Shillings four Pence.</p>
               <p>And going beyond the ſaid places, the Parties to agree with the Carr-men.</p>
               <p>Alſo from any the Wharfs aforeſaid to <hi>Tower-ſtreet, Bi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhops-gate-ſtreet</hi> within, <hi>Corn-Hill,</hi> and other places of like diſtance up the Hill, with fourteen Hundred Weight, not excee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding eighteen Hundred Weight; Two and Twenty Pence.</p>
               <p>In which may be included,</p>
               <p>Twenty Pieces of Raiſins, a Load of Raiſins of the Sun, ſix Bags of Pepper, ſix ordinary Bags of Galls, three great Bags of Galls, ſix Bales and Barrels of Indico, ſix Bales of Grogram Yarn, ſix Bales of <hi>Turky</hi> Silk, five Hogſheads of Cloves, four Bales of Calicoes, three Hogſheads of Wines, two Cheſts of Sugar or any other Goods of the like Weight, five Hogſheads of Tobacco, not exceeding eighteen hundred Weight, Two and twenty Pence.</p>
               <p>Alſo from any the Wharfs aforeſaid to <hi>Broad-ſtreet, Loth-bury, Old-Jury, Baſſiſhaw, Coleman-ſtreet, Ironmonger-Lane,</hi> St. <hi>Laurence-Lane, Milk-ſtreet, Aldermanbury, Cheap-ſide, Wood-ſtreet, Friday-ſtreet, Bread-ſtreet,</hi> and places of the like diſtance, for any of the ſaid Goods of the ſame quantity and weight, for every Load, Two Shillings.</p>
               <p>Alſo from any the Wharfs aforeſaid to <hi>Tower-ſtreet, Grace-Church-ſtreet, Fen-Church-ſtreet, Biſhopſgate-ſtreet</hi> within, <hi>Corn-Hill,</hi> and other places of like diſtance up the Hill, with eight hundred Weight, not exceeding four<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen hundred Weight, Eighteen Pence.</p>
               <pb n="39" facs="tcp:32945:21"/>
               <p>In which may be included</p>
               <p>All Butts and Pipes of Wine, or a Pipe of Oyl, Packs of Can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vas, two Hogſheads or three Tierces, a Fat of Fuſtians, and all other Goods of the like bulk and weight, for every Load Eighteen Pence.</p>
               <p>And from any the Wharfs aforeſaid to <hi>Broad-ſtreet, Loth-bury, Old-Jury, Baſſiſhaw, Coleman-ſtreet, Ironmonger-Lane,</hi> St. <hi>Laurence-Lane, Milk-ſtreet, Aldermanbury, Cheap-ſide, Wood-ſtreet, Friday-ſtreet,</hi> and other places of like diſtance, for any other Goods of like load or weight, for every Load, Twenty Pence.</p>
               <p>Alſo from <hi>London-Bridge</hi> foot Weſt-ward to the <hi>Old-Swan, Cole-Harbor,</hi> the <hi>Three-Cranes, Queen-hith, Broken-Wharf, Pauls-Wharf, Puddle-Wharf,</hi> the <hi>Wardrobe,</hi> and to all other places not exceeding the <hi>Poultry, Cheap-ſide,</hi> or <hi>Newgate-Market,</hi> for thirteen hundred Weight, not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding eighteen hundred Weight; Two and twenty pence.</p>
               <p>And for every Load of Sea-coals, fourteen Pence; every Load to behalf a Chaldron; and one hundred Faggots the like Rate.</p>
               <p>And from all other Wharfs and places between <hi>London-Bridge</hi> and <hi>Temple-Barr</hi> to the ſame and places of like di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance, for every Load of Coals, fourteen Pence, every Load to be half a Chaldron; and an hundred of Faggots the like Rate.</p>
               <p>And to all the places Northward of the <hi>Poultry, Cheap-ſide, Newgate-Market, Holborn-Bridge</hi> and <hi>Fleet-ſtreet,</hi> for fourteen hundred weight, not exceeding eighteen hundred weight; Two Shillings two Pence.</p>
               <p>And from <hi>Tower-ſtreet, Grace-church-ſtreet, Fen-church-ſtreet, Biſhopſgate-ſtreet</hi> within, <hi>Corn-Hill,</hi> and other places of like diſtance, for every Pack of twenty Cloths, for ſix Bales of Cloths and Kerſies, ſix Bales of Pepper, ſix Barrels of Indico, five Hogſheads of Cloves, and for other Goods not
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:32945:22"/> herein mentioned, of like weight, to the water-ſide, Six<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen Pence.</p>
               <p>And from <hi>Broad-ſtreet, Lothbury, Old-Jury, Baſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhaw, Coleman-ſtreet, Ironmonger-Lane,</hi> St. <hi>Laurence-Lane, Milk-ſtreet, Aldermanbury, Cheap-ſide, Wood-ſtreet, Friday-ſtreet, Bread-ſtreet,</hi> and other places of like diſtance to the water-ſide for the like weight, Twenty Pence.</p>
               <p>And for places nearer or of leſs diſtance, the Parties hiring and to be hired, are to make Agreement anſwerably or proportio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nably to the Rates before-mentioned.</p>
               <p>And if any Car-man ſhall take for his Labour and Hire, above the Rates before limited and appointed, and the ſame be duly proved by the teſtimony of one or more credible witneſs or witneſſes before the Lord Mayor, or any two of His Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties Juſtices of the Peace or otherwiſe within the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> ſuch Car-man ſhall ſuffer Impriſonment by the ſpace of one and twenty days without Bail or Mainpriſe, according to the Statute in this behalf, and ſhall undergo ſuch further Pains and Penalties as by the Law may be inflicted for the ſaid Offence.</p>
               <p>And to the end that all Car-men may be encouraged duly to obſerve the ſeveral Orders and Rates herein before limited and appointed; <hi>It is further Ordered,</hi> That if any Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chant, Tradeſman, or others, ſhall at any time hereafter refuſe to pay to any Car-man or Car-men his and their Hire or Wages, according to the ſeveral Rates herein before Ordered and appointed, that then it ſhall be lawful: <hi>And it is here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by Ordered,</hi> That ſuch Car-man and Car-men do make his and their Complaint to the Preſident of <hi>Chriſts-Hoſpital,</hi> for the time being, or to any of His Majeſties Juſtices of the Peace within the ſaid City of <hi>London,</hi> who are hereby deſired to compel the Payment of ſuch Hire and Wages, and to enforce the due obſervance of all and every the Orders above-mentio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned, according to Law and Juſtice.</p>
               <pb n="41" facs="tcp:32945:22"/>
               <p>
                  <hi>And it is further Ordered,</hi> That it ſhall be free for all Merchants and others, that have occaſion to uſe Cars or Carts, to chuſe what Cars he or they ſhall pleaſe, except ſuch as ſtand for Wharf-work, Tackle-work, Crane-work, Shops and Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants Houſes, which are to ſtand in order, and be taken in turn.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Alſo,</hi> That any Carman, who ſtands with his empty Car next to any Goods that are to be Loaden, ſhall on the firſt demand Load the ſame, without any delay, or bargaining for any other Wages than before is limited, and the Owners of the Goods ſo carried ſhall pay the ſame Rates.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Farther, It is Ordered,</hi> That if any Merchant or other perſon whatſoever, ſhall cauſe any Car-man to ſtay or attend at his Houſe, Shop, Ware-houſe, or Cellar, with his loaden Car, above half an hour before he unloads, ſuch Car-man being willing to help to unload the ſame, ſuch Merchants or others ſhall pay ſuch Car-men after the rate of twelve Pence an Hour, after the ſaid firſt half Hour for his Attendance.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And</hi> whereas the Rule, Overſight, and Government of the Cars, Carts, Carters, and Car-men, and of all other perſon or perſons whatſoever working any Car or Carts within the City of <hi>London</hi> and Liberties thereof, by Act of <hi>Common-Council</hi> of the one and twentieth day of <hi>June, 1665.</hi> is in the Preſident and Governours of <hi>Chriſts-Hoſpital;</hi> the ſaid Preſident and Governours are deſired by this Court forthwith to cauſe every Car or Cart which ſhall be licenſed to work with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the ſaid City and Liberties thereof to be numbred with Fi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gures upon a piece of Braſs to be fixed upon every Car or Cart, and the Car-mans name in ſuch Figures to be fairly Registred in a Book to be kept in <hi>Chriſts-Hoſpital,</hi> there at any time to be ſeen, to the end that if any Car-man ſhall not conform to the Rates aforeſaid, or ſhall refuſe to carry Goods at ſuch Rates, or ſhall exact greater Rates or Prices than is afore expreſſed, the Merchant or any other Citizen or Citizens,
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:32945:23"/> or others, knowing what Figure is upon the Cart, may the more readily find out who is the Worker thereof.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Further,</hi> If any Car-man or Carter ſhall not conform to the Rates aforeſaid, or ſhall refuſe to carry Goods for ſuch Rates, or exact greater Rates than herein is appointed, or ſhall work without the aforeſaid piece of Braſs fixed upon his Car or Cart, and the ſame be complained of to the ſaid Preſident and Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nours of the ſaid Hoſpital or any four of them, upon teſtimony of or for the party grieved, or any credible perſon on his be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half, they are hereby deſired to ſuſpend ſuch perſon from wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king any Car or Cart within the City of <hi>London</hi> and Liberties thereof, until he hath made ſatisfaction to the party grieved, and fixed the ſaid piece of Braſs upon his Car or Cart.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And</hi> the ſaid Preſident and Governours, and any four or more of them, are deſired by this Court to meet every <hi>Tueſday,</hi> in <hi>Chriſts-Hoſpital,</hi> at Two of the Clock in the Afternoon, to hear and determin all complaints that ſhall be made by any Merchant or Citizen againſt any Car-man whatſoever.</p>
               <p>And for prevention of future damages to the Merchants and others, and ſuppreſſing of unruly and diſorderly Car-men, and for avoiding of danger by unruly Horſes, it is thought fit and Ordered by this Court, and the ſaid Preſident and Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nours, or any four of them, are hereby deſired to nominate and appoint Street-men, ſuch as they ſhall think fit, to be Over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeers of the ſaid Car-men, to ſee and take care that Merchants and other Citizens Goods be well and faithfully carried and delivered at the Rates and Prizes aforeſaid, without any exaction, hindrance or diſturbance, and that able perſons, none under the age of eighteen years, be employed to manage their Horſes or Carts.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And</hi> whereas ſeveral Differences and Controverſies do daily ariſe between Car-man and Car-man concerning their Work and Labour, to the great diſturbance of the Kings Liege People, and to the manifeſt hindrance and obſtruction of the preſent
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:32945:23"/> carriage of Goods and Merchandizes; <hi>It is further Ordered,</hi> That the Wardens of the Fellowſhip of Car-men for the time being, or any two of them, having notice of ſuch Difference or Diſturbance, ſhall forthwith cauſe ſuch Car-man, between whom ſuch Difference and controverſie ſhall ariſe, to be brought before them, who are hereby Ordered and Deſired to hear, mediate, and determin the ſame. And in caſe any Car-man or Car-men ſhall at any time hereafter neglect, or obſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nately refuſe to yield Obedience to ſuch Order and Determina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, as ſhall be by the ſaid Wardens of the ſaid Fellowſhip of Car-men, or any two of them, made therein; That then and in every ſuch Caſe, <hi>It is hereby Ordered,</hi> That the ſaid Wardens of the ſaid Fellowſhip of Car-men for the time being, or any two of them, by whom ſuch Order or Determination was made, do cauſe ſuch Car-man or Carmen to be brought before the Preſident of <hi>Chriſts-Hoſpital</hi> for the time being, or any of His Majeſties Juſtices of the Peace within the ſaid City of <hi>London,</hi> who are hereby deſired to inflict ſuch Puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment upon ſuch diſobedient and refractory perſon and perſons, as ſhall be moſt agreeable to Law and Juſtice, or otherwiſe to cauſe ſuch perſon or perſons to find Sureties perſonally to appear at the next General Seſſions of the Peace, to be holden for the City of <hi>London,</hi> at <hi>Juſtice-Hall</hi> aforeſaid, then and there to anſwer his and their Diſobedience and Contempt, and ſuch other matters, as on His Majeſties behalf ſhall be then and there objected againſt him or them, and not to depart the Court without Licence.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="note">
               <pb n="44" facs="tcp:32945:24"/>
               <p>
                  <hi>NOte,</hi> That all the Perſons that live at St. <hi>Giles</hi>'s, St. <hi>Katherines,</hi> and other places forth of this City, and keep Carts, are under no regulation, and do not only take away the Car-mens Labour, that are Free-men of <hi>London,</hi> but come into <hi>London</hi> with two, three, and ſometimes more Horſes in their Carts.</p>
               <p>The Traders in Fuel within and without this City, peſter the Streets with their Carts, take away the Labour of the Car-men, go with as many Horſes as they pleaſe, and are un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der no regulation whatſoever, Beſides the stops which Coaches make in the Streets.</p>
               <p>If Carts were aſſigned for the Carriage of Fuel, out of the Number of Four Hundred and Twenty, now allowed by the Governours of <hi>Chriſts-Hoſpital,</hi> no Citizen of <hi>London</hi> would have cauſe to complain of the stoppage of the Streets.</p>
            </div>
            <pb facs="tcp:32945:24"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
